<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
 Licensed to the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) under one
 or more contributor license agreements.  See the NOTICE file
 distributed with this work for additional information
 regarding copyright ownership.  The ASF licenses this file
 to you under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the
 "License"); you may not use this file except in compliance
 with the License.  You may obtain a copy of the License at

   http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

 Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing,
 software distributed under the License is distributed on an
 "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY
 KIND, either express or implied.  See the License for the
 specific language governing permissions and limitations
 under the License.
-->
<document>
 <properties>
  <title>Fulcrum</title>
  <author email="jvanzyl@apache.org">Jason van Zyl</author>
  <author email="quintonm@bellsouth.net">Quinton McCombs</author>
 </properties>

 <body>

 <section name="What is Fulcrum?">
   <p>
     Fulcrum was originally created as part of the Turbine 3 effort.  The idea
     was to be able to decouple the services from Turbine 2 allowing them to be
     used on both projects. Turbine 4 uses now (2017) more than 15 Fulcrum components.
   </p>
   <p>
     Fulcrum has evolved into a component repository based on the Avalon framework.
     Each service is being converted into a stand alone component that can
     be released independently of the other components.  This will allow the
     Turbine project to to release components as they change instead of having
     to release everything at once.  This will also allow other projects to take advantage
     of these components.
   </p>
 </section>

 <section name="Container compatibility">
   <p>
     All components are compatible in Avalon's ECM container.  Any dependencies
     on other components, system properties, or context elements are clearly
     documented in the docs for each component.
   </p>
   <p>
    Additionally, Fulcrum offers the <a href="https://turbine.apache.org/fulcrum/fulcrum-yaafi/">Yaafi component</a>.  Yaafi (Yet Another Avalon Framework
    Implementation) is a very simple container that is meant to be used with singleton
    components.  It is perfect for unit testing your components.  You can then run them in
    any other Avalon container like ECM, Phoenix, Excalibur, etc..
   </p>
 </section>
 
 <section name="Where do I get releases?">

 <p>
    Download the current main release sources and binaries through the Apache mirror system at 
    <a href="http://www.apache.org/dyn/closer.cgi/turbine/fulcrum/">the fulcrum download site</a>.
  </p>

</section>

<section name="How do I contribute, give feedback, fix bugs and so on?">

<ul>
    <li>
        We have a <a href="https://turbine.apache.org/contact.html">Turbine mailing
        lists</a> for discussion.</li>
    <li>
        Create issues and comments in Apache JIRA system <a href="https://issues.apache.org/jira/issues/?jql=project+%3D+TRB+AND+component+%3D+Fulcrum">Turbine (Component Fulcrum)
        </a></li>
    <li>
        You can also access the <a href="https://svn.apache.org/viewvc/turbine/fulcrum/trunk/">Turbine Fulcrum SVN
        repository</a></li>

    <li>
        You can access the <a href="https://github.com/apache/turbine-fulcrum/">Turbine Fulcrum sub project Git (read only)
        repository</a></li>   
  
 
</ul>

</section>

 </body>
</document>
