<?xml version="1.0"?>

<document>

  <properties>
    <title>Fulcrum OSWorkflow Example Application</title>
    <author email="epugh@upstate.com">Eric Pugh</author>
  </properties>

  <body>

  <section name="Overview">
    <p>
      This is a small example application using the Turbine framework with the Fulcrum Workflow component. 
    </p>
  
    <p>
      It provides a similar demonstration using the Turbine framework to the example application included in
      the OpenSymphony OSWorkflow distriubution.  This includes demostrating running BeanShell and BSF scripts, 
      user authenctication etc..
    </p>
    <p>
      It leverages the Turbine user by storing the user information in runData.getUser() object.  The persistence 
      mechanism is in memory, but it is very easy to swap in the JDBC persistence engine for OSWorkflow and use the
      same demo.
    </p>
    
    <p>
      In this distribution is a little workflow pull tool that is used in the .vm templates as $workflow that allows
      easy access to some commonly used functions of the workflow service.
    </p>
    <p>
    <a href="screen1.png" target="_OUT">Workflows Screen</a><br/>
    <a href="screen2.png" target="_OUT">Workflow Detail Screen</a>
    </p>
    
    <p>
      Feedback is warmly appreciated!
    </p>
  </section>
  
  <section name="Build and Deploy Example">
	<p>
	  To run this example, first check the source code out from CVS.  The .war file is not online as it is 10 megabytes, and Maven will
	  download any of the dependencies that you don't already have!  Also, part of this example is to show a sample project structure
	  as well.  By downloading/building/ and deploying you get the full lifecycle.
	</p>
    <p>
      To run this example, run 'maven war' from the fulcrum/osworkflow/example directory.  This will produce the WAR
      file that you need to deploy to your Tomcat webapp.  Make sure the name of the war file is changed to 'fulcrum-osworkflow-example'
      as the internal links expect that name.
    </p>

  </section>

</body>
</document>
